gate2shop.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy and Cookies Policy - SafeCharge

### Privacy and Cookies Policy

This Privacy and Cookies Policy is intended for those browsing/using Safecharge.com and other Safecharge group informative websites (jointly: “Site”) owned and operated by the Safecharge International Group Limited and its affiliates and subsidiaries (“we” or “us”) and describes and explains how we treat information that is received and/or collected, when received or collected, through your use of the Site.

### Your consent

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY AND COOKIES POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT ACCESS/USE THE SITE.

By using the Site you agree and accept the terms of this Privacy and Cookies Policy and consent to the collection and use of information in the manner set out in this Privacy and Cookies Policy. We encourage you to review this Privacy and Cookies Policy carefully and to periodically refer to it so that you understand it and subsequent changes if any. We reserve the right to change this Privacy and Cookies Policy with immediate effect and we will post an appropriate notification.

### The information we collect

We respect your right to privacy. You do not have to provide us with any personally identifying information.

Every time you browse/use the Site we may record the following information: transactional information based on activities on the website, Internet Protocol address, browser information and application numbers, Cookies; and Geographical location.

Where you wish to take advantage of special services that we may offer from time to time, we may request that you provide certain additional information and this statement (as may be amended from time to time) shall apply as well as the terms of use and privacy guidelines specific to such services, where available.

We may offer you the opportunity to subscribe to receive certain updates or marketing materials. You may choose to ‘unsubscribe’ from receiving these at any time. When you sign up, subscribe, fill out a form, comment, send us an e-mail or ask us to respond to you or when you communicate with us in any other way (“Communication”), we retain the information that you have included in the respective Communication as well as our responses to such Communication. We may associate such information with information received from other channels such as your Site usage information.

### Cookies

We may set cookies and related standard technologies (jointly: “cookies”) as you visit the Site, use our online products and services or view our products and offers. We may also use third party cookies or allow third parties to set cookies. A cookie is a small amount of data which is stored on your computer or device for the purpose of identifying the browser or product during interactions. We also use cookies to track the interest and usage patterns of our users so we can achieve our goals as set forth in the “HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION” chapter below.

You can configure your web browser not to accept cookies, although this may affect how you see and are able to use the Site and online products and services. You can also learn more about cookies by visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browser.

Cookies are typically divided into four main types, we may use some or all:

  * **Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies that are required for the operation of a website. They include, for example, cookies that enable users to log into secure areas of a website, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.
  * **Analytical/performance cookies**. These types of cookies allow providers to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around their website when they are using it. This assists providers in improving the way their website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * **Functionality cookies**. These are used to recognise users when they return to a website. They enable the personalisation of content, the recognition of users and remember user preferences (for example, their choice of language or region).
  * **Targeting cookies**. These cookies record a user’s visit to a website, the individual pages visited and the links followed. If the cookie is set by a third party (for example, an advertising network) which also monitors traffic on other websites, this type of cookies may also be used to track a user’s movements across different website and to create profiles of their general online behaviour. Information collected by tracking cookies is commonly used to serve users with targeted online advertising.

Below you will find the list of cookies used by us and a description of what each cookie is designed to accomplish, the list may be updated from time to time and you are invited to check back on a regular basis. Please note the difference between a ‘session cookie’ (i.e. expires at the end of the session) and a ‘persistent cookie’ which does not expire at the end of the session.

**Cookie name** | **  Purpose / description **  
---|---  
PHPSESSID | Stores a unique identifier for browser session. This is an analytical session cookie.  
sc_referer | Stores the specific URL from which the user originated. This is an analytical persistent cookie.  
viewed_cookie_policy | Stores user’s preference with respect to this policy. This is a functional persistent cookie.  
wfvt | Wordfence cookies prevent fraud and improve the security of the website  
wordfence | Wordfence cookies prevent fraud and improve the security of the website  
incap_ses | Incapsula cookie improves performance and security on the website  
visid_incap | Incapsula visitor id cookie is needed to improve performance and security on the website  
  
### Google Analytics

We use the following Google Analytics cookies to help us as an analytics tool to measure how users interact with the Site: _utma, _utmb, _utmc and _utmz (_utmc is a session cookies and the others are persistent with an expiry date). For more information on the Google Analytics cookies please visit <http://www.google.com/analytics/>

### Investis cookies

Certain information under the “INVESTORS” tab is displayed through the use of services provided by SafeCharge’s vendor Investis. Below you will find the names of the cookies set by Investis in order to deliver their respective services and a description of what each cookie is designed to accomplish.

**Cookie name** | **  Purpose / description **  
---|---  
ASP.NET_SessionId | Stores a unique identifier for browser session. This is an analytical session cookie.  
investors-safecharge-com#lang | Stores language preference. This is a functional session cookie.  
_parentURL | Used for RNS tool and is used for iFrame resizer. This is a performance session cookie.  
  
Google Analytics cookies are also used in the ‘INVESTORS’ tab. For more information please see above under ‘Google Analytics”.

### How we use the information

We may use the information collected to optimize performance, improve usability, provide additional or customized offerings, track status indicator, make sure things are working properly, enhance the experience on the Site and for use in aggregate for commercial purposes such as marketing and promotions.

We may share information internally as well with third parties, such as trusted suppliers, business partners, advertisers and search engines. However, unless specifically indicated in this document, such information is collected and shared without any association to your personally identifying information so that you remain anonymous.

We may share and/or transfer information including personally identifying information internally as well as with government bodies and law enforcement agencies (where lawfully instructed or required), successors in title to the respective business (i.e. if we become involved in any form of merger or acquisition) and to suppliers we engage to process data on our behalf.

In relation to the information we gain as part of a Communication we may use it to acknowledge your comments and/or reply to your questions and we may store it in case we need to correspond at a later date. We will not use the contact details you provide us for marketing messages without your consent.

### Internet based-transfers

Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Therefore by browsing the Site and communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal data in this way.

### Third party products and services

The Site may contain third party offers, products and services and links to other websites. By choosing these, you will be leaving our Site and receiving/using products and services from third parties or transferred to online merchants or other third party sites, all of which are not under our control and are not monitored or reviewed by us.

Inclusion of a link to third party website, product or service is for your convenience only and such inclusion does not imply affiliation, endorsement or adoption by us.  If we share information with third parties we shall do so in compliance with our Privacy and Cookies Policy. Third party products, services or sites may contain information or material that is illegal, unreasonable or that some people may find inappropriate or offensive.

You acknowledge that we assume no responsibility or liability whatsoever for such third party products or services or to the content or privacy practices of those third parties, this Privacy and Cookies Policy and the Terms of Use do not apply to the third party products, services or websites or to information collected by such third parties.

Before using third party sites, you should read and understand those sites’/product’s/services’ terms and conditions and privacy policies to ensure you agree to their terms.

You are knowingly and voluntarily assuming all risks of using third party products, services and sites and that we shall have no liability whatsoever with respect to such third party sites, products and services and your usage of them.

### Security

We have security measures in place to prevent unauthorized access to and protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Although we take reasonable steps to safeguard information, we cannot be responsible for the acts of those who gain unauthorized access and we make no warranty, express, implied or otherwise, that we will prevent such access.

### Controlling your information

Where we hold personal information about you, you may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to Safecharge International Group Limited at the address as it appears under the ‘About Us’ tab on our Site.

### Questions?

Should you have other questions or concerns about this Privacy and Cookies Policy please see the ‘Contact Us’ tab on our Site.

Date of last update to this document: June 2017

Scroll to top
